<?xml version="1.0"?>

<document>

  <properties>
    <title>Plexus</title>
    <author email="jason@zenplex.com">Jason van Zyl</author>
  </properties>

  <body>

  <section name="Getting Started">
    <p>
      This small guide will get you up and running with Plexus as fast as
      possible. It is assumed that:
    </p>
    
    <ul>
      <li>You have a JDK installed on your machine.</li>
      <li>You have <a href="http://maven.apache.org">Maven</a> installed on your machine.</li>
    </ul>
    
    <subsection name="Checking out the Plexus sources">
      
      <p>
        Execute the following commands to check out the sources for the Plexus
        container, the Plexus components and the Plexus Maven plug-in:
      </p>
    
    
      <source><![CDATA[
      
       cvs -d :pserver:anonymous@cvs.codehaus.org:/scm/cvs login
       
       <enter>
       
       cvs -z3 -d :pserver:anonymous@cvs.codehaus.org:/scm/cvs co plexus
      
      ]]></source>
    
      <p>
        Now all you need to do is run the getting-started script for your given
        platform. This will execute the standard 'getting-started' that Maven projects tend 
        to provide in order to get new users up and running quickly. Unfortunately we must use 
        native scripts at the moment due to some quirks with Maven's reactor. After you have 
        executed this script you will have everything you need on your machine to start your 
        first Plexus application.
      </p>
    
    </subsection>
    
    <subsection name="Using the Plexus Maven plug-in">
      
      <p>
        The Plexus Maven plug-in will help you to develop your Plexus
        application by doing the following:
      </p>
      
      <ul>
        <li>Providing goals to help generate Plexus components.</li>
        <li>Providing goals to help generate Plexus component tests.</li>
        <li>Providing goals to help assemble a Plexus application runtime.</li>
      </ul>

      <p>
        In order to use the Plexus Maven plug-in you must install so that it
        is registered with Maven. You can either build the plug-in your self
        from sources or you may just download the plug-in from <a href="">here</a>.
      </p>

    </subsection>
    
  </section>

</body>
</document>
